Josiah Storrie

Denver, Colorado | 303-669-6952 | jpstorrie@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog

FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER

A Full Stack Web Developer experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript/React based programming and a background in the restaurant industry. With a strong desire for continuous learning and growth in the Software Engineering field, I bring strong team-oriented skills in communication and collaboration, along with the ability to quickly pivot and adapt to change. My passion for detail-oriented problem-solving drew me towards web development, where my tenacity and accountability have played a crucial role in successfully guiding project completion.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, JavaScript, Ruby, Rails, Object-Oriented Programming, HTML, CSS, SQL, Postgres, BootStrap, TailwindCSS, DaisyUI, Rest APIs, Active Record, Active Storage

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

KeepSight - Github

A website to store photos, videos, and achievements of your children.

- Built a Ruby on Rails backend API utilizing PostgreSQL to store data
- Leveraged Active Storage to store and download videos and photos
- Utilized React and TailwindCSS with DaisyUI for user-friendly GUI
- Applied BCrypt to secure and authenticate user data safely

Le Musik - Github

Browse a predefined collection of albums, artists, and tracks

- Constructed a Ruby on Rails backend with an emphasis on exploring the most recent stable releases of all assets
- Enabled React and Bootstrap for responsive UI
- Employed React Bootstrap component library for rapid deployment

Gamer's Guide - Github

Game Wiki/Forum for a community of users to learn and help others

- Constructed Ruby on Rails backend for effective data management
- Implemented BootStrap 5.0 for easy-to-use UI.
- Assembled React frontend for speed, efficiency, and code reusability.

EXPERIENCE

Piripi Restaurant - Erie, CO Sous Chef (Kitchen Lead)

04/2021 - 12/2022 04/2022 - 12/2022

- Supervised kitchen operations to ensure smooth execution and meet business objectives while delivering high
- quality customer satisfaction Led, trained, and organized kitchen employees and their tasks in a fast-paced, high-stress environment to ensure
- quality and consistency in production Station Chef 08/2021 - 04/2022

Collaborated with the culinary team to ensure high-quality food and service Demonstrated initiative by proactively identifying areas for improvement in kitchen operations, resulting in increased

Junior Chef 04/2021 - 08/2021

- Communicated effectively with customers to understand their dietary preferences and accommodate their needs, resulting in positive reviews and repeat business.
- Displayed adaptability and flexibility by quickly adjusting to changes in the kitchen environment, such as new recipes or procedures.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School - Denver, CO

efficiency and productivity.

12/2022 - 03/2023

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, React, JavaScript immersive program

Colorado Virtual Academy - Lakewood, CO

08/2018 - 06/2021

High School Diploma with a focus on programming electives